No!
不…不要
Ring King!
戒…戒王陛下
Go to safety now!
快逃
Yes!
是
This is the third I've taken down.
这已经是第三只了
Its power ran out after a few swings last time.
之前明明挥一下就没力了
It's thanks to Her Highness' kiss earlier.
那是多亏公主刚刚的吻
The power of the bond between the two of you
夫妻之间的情意强度
is the power source of the ring.
就是戒指的力量
It's the princess' duty to power the Ring King's campaign.
成为国王出征的力量 也是公主的职责
That was why Hime...
所以小姬才会…
But it's too challenging for you
不过以现在的你来说
to maintain the power for too long.
应该没办法撑太久
But don't worry.
但是别担心
I'll assist you along the way.
我也会从旁协助
Speaking of that, are you actually very strong, Gramps?
话说小姬的爷爷该不会很强吧
They called you Great Sage Asparagus...
听说你是贤者阿斯帕拉戈斯…
It's Alabaster!
是阿拉巴斯塔啦
What was that?
怎么了
An enemy unlike any other.
跟之前的家伙不同
The Ring of Light...
光之戒…
Ring King...
戒王
That figure...
那个模样…
It can't be!
不…不会吧
Knight of the Abyss King!
居然是深渊王的骑士
Hime gave me the power to protect her.
小姬已经给了我力量
I can keep going!
我还能继续上
No!
不行
What's with that wind?
这阵风是怎么回事
This hurts a lot.
虽然痛得要命
But I'm still alive. Did the ring's power save me?
但是只受了这点程度的小伤 都是多亏了戒指吗
Satou, run for your life!
佐藤 快逃吧
Huh!?
什么
Stop yapping! Go!
别说了 快点
What's the deal now?
搞什么啊
They sent in some nasty monsters.
居然派那种狠角色过来
It's evident they fear the Ring King's power.
表示他们真的很畏惧戒王的力量吗
What was that thing?
那是什么东西
I can't even close in on it.
连接近都接近不了
That was the Knight of the Abyss King.
那是深渊王的骑士
It's a terrifying monster capable of commanding powerful magic!
是能操控强力魔法的可怕魔物
Magic!?
魔法?
Can't we fight that with the ring's power?
难道没办法用戒指的力量应付吗
Save that conversation for later.
这件事晚点再说
I'll buy us some time.
我来争取时间
Incredible. What was that?
好…好厉害 这是什么
The control of mana with the power of will that abides by the philosophy of nature.
用遵循世界哲理的意志之力 操控万物的魔素…
In other words, it's magic.
这也是魔法
All right. Go through here.
好了 只要穿过那里就行了
Gramps.
爷爷
Darn it! It got ahead of us!
糟糕 她绕到我们前面了吗
The prince?
皇子
Quick!
快走
There is a carriage on the other side.
另一头有马车
Hold on. Are you asking us to flee from the castle?
等一下 你要我们逃到城外吗
Hime is still inside!
小姬还在里面…
You need not worry about that.
不用担心这件事
Come with me now.
总之你们先跟我来
I'm so glad you're safe.
幸好你没事
Hime...
小姬…
Monsters managed to seize the southern tower as well.
结果南边的塔也被魔物闯入了
I took it upon myself to bring the princess to safety
我决定在公主陷入危险之前
before she was in danger.
把她带离到安全的地方
Thanks for getting us out.
谢谢你刚才救了我们
You are...
你是…
My name is Marmarugias Gisaras.
我的名字 叫马尔玛利基亚斯·基萨拉斯
The Second Prince of the Gisaras Empire,
是光之国诺卡那堤卡的邻国
the neighbouring country of Nokanatika.
帝国基萨拉斯的第二皇子
Ma... Mar... Marugias...
马…马尔…马尔戈利达先生?
Anyway, thanks.
谢谢你
You can call me Marse.
叫我马尔斯就行了
More importantly, Great Sage,
话说回来 贤者大人
will the kingdom be all right?
王国不会有事吧
At the moment, the Abyss King is going after
深渊王现阶段的目标
the Ring King and his ring.
是戒王和他持有的戒指
When he knows we've left the castle,
只要知道我们不在城堡
the monsters will start searching for us.
应该就会开始搜寻我们
There should be no other casualties.
不会再出现更多的伤亡
However...
但是…
Without the power of light,
没有光之力
it's almost impossible to defeat a foe like the knight of the Abyss King.
很难除掉像深渊王的骑士那种 高等的魔物
Doesn't that mean I have to be the one to defeat it?
果然还是只能由我来想办法了
We are now on the run
就是因为你的力量不够
because you still lack the power.
我们才要逃跑
What do you mean I lack the power?
不够是什么意思
As the Ring King, your power is still very faint.
你身为戒王 现在力量还很微弱
For your full power to manifest,
如果想让力量变得完整
you must gather the other four rings.
还需要另外四只戒指
Four more rings...
还需要四只…
I thought this was a wedding ring!
这不是婚戒吗
In other words...
也就是说
Correct. Your next mission
没错 你接下来…
is to marry the other four princesses
还要和另外四位公主结婚
and receive their rings!
得到她们的戒指
Isn't that polygamy?
那样不是重婚吗
That's the duty of the Ring King.
戒王就是这样的存在
There's nothing to worry about.
没有任何问题
Well? Isn't this exciting?
怎么样 是不是很兴奋啊
There are five princesses in total.
是五位公主哦
-Wait! Hold on! -This is a man's greatest dream!
-不 这…这个嘛 -这对男人来说是最幸福的事
No! I'm already married to Hime.
不 但我已经有小姬了
I'm not interested in that at all.
我可是一点也不兴奋
TALES OF WEDDING RINGS
《婚戒物语》
There are only two rooms available.
只剩两间空房
The men will stay in one.
那我们三名男性住一间
No.
不
It's not safe to leave Krystal in the room all alone.
让克莉丝朵一个人待着 可能会有危险
I'll share a room with her...
就让她跟我住同一间房
No way.
我才不要
Ouch!
打击
In that case, you and your husband can take a room.
那就请身为丈夫的你和她同房吧
All right. Before we move on tomorrow,
好了 在明天正式行动前
let me brief you on the true duty
我先简单跟你们说一下吧
of the legendary Ring King.
戒王真正的使命究竟是什么
Long ago,
很久以前
the Abyss King intended to make this world submit to his dark power.
深渊王打算让这个世界 臣服于他的黑暗力量之下
Endless hordes of monsters attack, bringing great torment to the people.
永无止尽的魔物来袭 让人们的心饱受煎熬
Many countries perished amidst the looming doom.
许多国家笼罩在死亡的阴影中消失
To repel this force of darkness,
戒王为了驱逐这片黑暗
the Ring King created rings infused with magical power.
创造了注入魔力的戒指
Each ring commands an element: Light, fire, water, wind, and earth.
那就是光 火 水 风 土
Five rings, five different powers.
五种力量的戒指
The Ring King used their powers
戒王利用它们的力量
to seal the Abyss King away after an extensive battle for survival.
经过漫长的死斗终于封杀深渊王
The five rings
后来 五只戒指
were handed over to his five wives
由身为戒王妻子的五位公主
and brought back to their respective five countries,
分别带回五个国家
and have been passed down for generations,
世世代代传承
becoming five wedding rings that prove the princesses' bond with the Ring King.
成为证明公主 和戒王关系的五组婚戒
Now, the Abyss King has been resurrected.
然后现在深渊王复活
He is slowly regaining his power.
渐渐地取回他的力量
The Ring King's duty
戒王的使命
is to collect all five rings from the five princesses
是再次从五位公主手中 取得五只戒指
so he can seal the Abyss King away with their powers.
用它们的力量封印深渊王
The Ring King's duty...
这就是戒王的使命…
Don't be concerned about what he said earlier.
刚才的那些话
Don't overthink.
你不需要在意
Our marriage is only for show anyway.
毕竟我们的婚姻只不过是形式
But I...
不 我…
Satou?
佐藤
Did I get hurt in the fight?
被打伤了吗
I thought the ring protected me.
我还以为自己没事
Take it off.
脱掉
Isn't it too quick to jump to this part?
怎么能一下子就做这种大胆的事
Now is not the time to fool around!
这种时候就别开玩笑了
This is all my fault.
都是我害的
No. I got injured because I got carried away.
不 是我得意忘形才会搞成这样
No.
不对
It was my fault for choosing you.
都怪我选了你
Hime!
小姬
Where did she go?
她跑到哪去了
Mr. Marse.
马尔斯…先生
What's the matter?
怎么了
Did you see Hime coming through?
你有看到小姬吗
Princess Krystal ran past me just now.
克莉丝朵公主刚刚从这里跑过去了
I see.
原来如此
The Ring King and the Ring Princesses.
戒王和戒指公主
It's a heavy burden to bear.
如此沉重的使命
It is natural you'd feel overwhelmed.
的确会让人难以承受吧
No, it's not that bad...
不 没这么夸张啦
In fact, I have to thank you.
我啊 其实很感谢你
To be honest with you, it was a relief to be freed from my duty
老实说 能摆脱戒王的使命
as the Ring King.
让我松了一口气
You followed her to this world
你是为了追回她
to win her back, right?
才从异世界过来的吧
She must mean a lot to you.
你一定很重视她
Not really, I was only...
没有啦 我只是…
You left your life behind
为了追求心爱的人
in pursuit of love.
抛弃自己过去生活的世界
It's not easy.
这不是轻易就能办到的事
Take pride in that.
很值得骄傲
Sorry, I took up too much of your time.
抱歉 我绊住你了
She should be in the backyard up ahead.
她应该就在前面一点的后院
Thanks.
好
Thank you!
谢谢你
I wish
如果我…
I could have his courage.
也有跟他一样的勇气就好了
Satou...
佐藤…
I...
我…
I like you, Hime.
我…喜欢小姬
And I don't mean our friendship.
不是朋友之间的喜欢
I really like you.
而是真的喜欢你
I am here
我现在会在这里
because of my own decision.
是我自己的选择
I chose this.
是我自己决定的结果
You shouldn't blame yourself for our circumstances.
所以你不需要感到有责任
You've made up your mind.
原来你已经下定决心了啊
I've been so frustrated.
别看我这样 我一直很烦恼
I wanted to forget my life as Hime Nonaka
决定忘掉身为野中姬乃的一切
and fulfil my duty as the Princess of Light.
完成身为光戒公主的使命
For the fate of this world,
为了这个世界
I was willing to marry a complete stranger
我愿意和不认识的人结婚
and make even greater sacrifices.
甚至付出更多
But when you followed me to this world,
但是都怪你追上来
I love every bit of that resolve.
让我的决心通通消失了
All because I finally had the chance to marry someone I really liked.
因为我终于有机会 和自己真正喜欢的人结婚了
With that said, my husband is the Ring King.
但是我的丈夫会成为戒王
He gets hurt in battle.
不只会在战斗中受伤
He's obligated to marry other princesses.
还得和其他公主们结婚
I don't want to see the man I like go through these.
我不想看到最喜欢的人变成这样
Hime...
小姬…
Sorry. I...
对不起 我…
I've been too selfish.
满脑子都只想着自己
No, that's not it.
不是的
I have to change.
我不要再这样了
I'll make up my mind this time.
这次我一定会下定决心
This marriage shouldn't be just a sham.
不只是形式
I want to be your real wife
我想作为真正的夫妻
and help you fulfil your duty as the Ring King.
和你一起完成戒指的使命
Hime...
小姬…
Satou...
佐藤…
Will you take me as your real wife?
我可以正式成为你的妻子吗
Yes.
好
-What now?
-怎么办
After everything we said just now...
因为刚刚说了那种话
It suddenly got so arousing.
感觉气氛变得好煽情
Satou!
佐藤
Yes?
是
I'm ready to be a real wife.
我已经做好成为妻子的准备了
Can I... really do this?
我真的…可以做下去吗
Though I've longed for this moment,
虽然我的确渴望做这件事
but this feels...
但是总觉得…
Satou...
佐藤…
What's wrong?
你怎么了
No.
不对
This isn't the way to do it.
不应该是这样的
Our first time should be much sweeter than this!
我和小姬的第一次应该更甜蜜一点
Huh!?
什么
It's wrong to simply go along with the mood!
像这样顺水推舟就做是不对的
My ten years' worth of love for you
我这十年来对小姬的心意
shouldn't be like this!
不应该以这种形式达成
I don't get it. You sound gross.
那是什么意思 好恶心
In other words,
总而言之
this isn't like us at all.
这样子一点也不像我们
We suddenly went from childhood friends to a married couple.
毕竟我们是从青梅竹马 一下子跳到夫妻的阶段
We can take our time to do
夫妻之间该做的事情
what a married couple does.
就让我们慢慢完成吧
You have a point.
说得也是
Well? Did you sleep well last night?
怎么样 昨晚有睡好吗
Safe and sound.
睡得很好
No way I could sleep after that!
怎么可能睡得着
Are you serious?
什么嘛
Did nothing happen afterwards?
后来什么事也没发生吗
The mood was perfect at the moment.
气氛明明那么好
You two are no fun!
真无聊
Did you see everything?
你看到了吗
Sorry, I misspoke.
抱歉 我失言了
It's the bond. That's the source of the Ring King's power.
情意 这就是戒王的力量来源
It's a good thing your bond has been strengthened.
你们的情意能加深是好事
Good morning to both of you.
早安 两位
It seems the problem has been solved.
看来问题已经解决了
Here, put this on.
来 穿上这个
Your clothes from the other world are too conspicuous here.
因为异界的衣服多少有点醒目
Time to move on.
那我们走吧
First, we are visiting the elves' tribe,
首先要前往的是知识民族
the nation of knowledge known as
精灵隐居的部落
Lomka of the Wind.
风之洛姆加
Elves? Like the people with pointy ears?
精灵指的是耳朵长长的精灵吗
Correct.
没错
The Ring of Wind is the heirloom of the elven royal family.
风之戒就是由精灵的王室传承
Besides, the elves are a race of beauty!
而且精灵是非常美丽的种族
Did that get your excited?
听到这句话是不是突然有干劲了
Well, Satou?
佐藤
Not at all.
才没有
Grandpa, stop it.
别这样 爷爷
I'm your only real wife!
你真正的妻子是我哦
I know.
我知道
Do you really?
你真的知道吗
Don't worry.
别担心啦
Unbelievable. Do you really understand?
受不了 你真的知道吗
The Ring King...
戒王…
A man from the other world...
来自外界的人
Utterly disgusting.
真是令人厌恶
Deep within the valley
在某座深谷的底下
is the homeland of the beautiful and intelligent race of elves.
是美丽又聪明的精灵们居住的土地
Long ago, this is the nexus of knowledge from across the world.
以前这个地方 是世界各地知识的汇集之地
It was a sacred place.
被视为神圣的场所
But 50 years ago,
但是在50年前
Lomka was surrounded by a barrier of gusts that came out of nowhere.
洛姆加被突如其来的暴风屏障围住
This barrier of gust has stopped
这就是阻挡许多种族入侵的
the invasions from other races.
暴风屏障
This nation is nothing like what it used to be.
这个国家也完全变了一个样
Grandpa, have you been here before?
爷爷 你有来过这里吗
That was a long time ago.
以前曾经来过
The barrier wasn't here when I came.
但我来的时候 还没有这种屏障
What is this thing?
这家伙是什么
Is this the Abyss King's monster?
这也是深渊王的魔物吗
No, this is a beast from the forest.
不 这只是森林的野兽
You can think of it as a bear.
就跟熊没两样
What? It's just a bear?
什么啊 原来是熊
So, this is just a wild animal.
所以只是普通的野生动物咯
It's probably not dangerous...
那应该没有危险…
You fool!
蠢蛋
What kind of fool would approach a wild animal like that?
哪有人会毫无防备接近野生动物
A bear from the forest can just be dangerous too!
森林里的熊也很危险好吗
I'm so sorry!
对不起
Oh no.
糟了
There's nowhere to run.
这样根本无路可逃
Over here!
快过来这里
The bear flew away.
熊飞走了
Who are you people?
你们是什么人
What are you humans doing here?
为什么人类会在这种地方
Long and pointy ears...
耳朵好长
Are they...
也就是说…
Sons of the Wind, thank you for saving us.
风之民 谢谢你们出手相救
We are...
我们是…
I am the Ring King.
我是戒王
I've come for your princess.
我是来见这个国家的公主
Hold on, Satou.
等一下 佐藤
Not all nations with rings are willing to join our cause.
并不是所有戒之国 都愿意协助我们哦
Is that so?
是这样吗
The Ring King... I see.
戒王…原来如此
We've heard the rumours.
我们的确有听过传闻
Very well. We'll take you to the palace.
好吧 我们带你们去王宫
However, things probably won't go as you wish.
只不过事情大概不会如你们所愿
To reach Lomka,
要前往洛姆加
you must pass through the roots of this giant tree.
就要通过这棵巨树的根部里面
Isn't this kind of inconvenient?
感觉有点不便
It's a safety measure.
是为了安全起见
Only smaller creatures can pass through it.
能通过这里的小型生物
That will minimise the damage.
不会造成多大的危害
Stronger monsters will be faltered by the gust barrier.
强大的魔物则会被风逼退
It's pretty good at its job.
相当可靠哦
This is the Lomka, the nation of the Ring of Wind.
这里就是风之戒国 洛姆加
I wonder what kind of person the elven princess is.
不知道精灵公主是怎样的人
What she is like doesn't really matter.
不管对方是怎样的人都没关系
I must collect the rings for the sake of this world.
为了这个世界取得戒指
Nothing comes before that.
没有比这更重要的事情
Huh?
奇怪
There's no one here.
没有半个人
She is hiding behind the throne!
她在王座后面
Is that the princess we're looking for?
她就是公主
She seems very wary of us.
感觉对我们充满戒心的样子
Ye... Yeah.
对…对啊
Are you the Ring King?
你就是戒王陛下
Yes!
没错
I am the hero from another world, Satou!
我是从异世界来的勇者佐藤
The other world!?
异世界?
Yes!
是的
Aren't you married?
你们是夫妻没错吧
Does that mean... you've done it?
也就是说 你们已经做过了吗
Well...
就是…
S...
做…
That's the first thing she wants to know?
这女孩怎么一开口就问这个
We haven't gotten to that part!
我们还没做过
Did you smooch?
做过接吻这件事了吗
That's it?
原来是这个
Well, you can put it that way.
呃…算是吧
No.
不行
I can't waver because of something so trivial.
我怎么能因为这种小事就动摇
He already has the Ring of Light.
光之戒已经在他手上了
To free the world from the evil of the Abyss King,
为了摆脱深渊王的威胁
please abide by the tradition and give him the ring...
请你遵循传承 将风之戒…
This is too lewd!
太…太龌龊了
You're asking me to touch his lips with mine!
竟然要我和别人互相碰嘴唇
Huh!?
咦
So gross...
好恶心
She ran off!
她跑走了
Ewwww...
恶…
Huh?
咦…
Huh!?
咦咦